Guide to the A. P. Watt and Son records, 1861-1971 [bulk 1880-1949]
The New York Public Library. Henry W. and Albert A. Berg Collection of English and American Literature.
A. P. Watt and Son records
1861-1971
1880-1949
Berg Coll MSS Watt
19277
Card catalog available.
A. P. Watt and Son
The New York Public Library. Henry W. and Albert A. Berg Collection of English and American Literature. Stephen A. Schwarzman Building Fifth Avenue at 42nd Street, New York, NY 10018-2788
ca. 2,468 items
This is a synthetic collection consisting of typescripts, manuscripts, correspondence, and legal and financial documents.
A. P. Watt and Son is a British literary agency. It was founded in 1875 by Alexander Pollock Watt.
The bulk of the materials were received from the files of A. P. Watt and Son.
This is a synthetic collection consisting of typescripts, manuscripts, correspondence, and legal and financial documents. The typescripts and manuscript consist of memoranda and miscellaneous items relating to Marie Corelli, Rudyard Kipling, William Somerset Maugham, and Herbert George Wells. The correspondence consists of letters from the firm, dating from 1879 to 1971, to Wystan Hugh Auden, Marie Corelli, Charles Garvice, Harold Paget, Michael Roberts, Bertha Vyver, H. G. Wells, the publishing firm Doubleday & Co., the literary agency of Field, Roscoe & Co., and others, as well as an undated letter relating to the firm from Sir Arthur Conan Doyle to Meyrick Jones, and letters drafted for A. P. Watt and Son by Sir Henry Rider Haggard, dated 1887. There are letters to A. P. Watt and Son from Maude Adams, J. W. Arrowsmith (Bristol, England), T. Foster Barham, Benn (Ernest) Ltd., Sir Walter Besant, John Buchan, Cassell & Co., Ernest V. Chandler, Marie Corelli, Doubleday, Page & Co., A. C. Doyle, Lady Jean (Leckie) Doyle, Louis Fabulet, Field, Roscoe & Co., William Hooker Gillette, Sir Henry Rider Haggard, William Heinemann Ltd., Edward Jenkins, Caroline (Balestier) Kipling, Rudyard Kipling, James Stanley Little, Low (Sampson) Marston & Co., H. L. Lucoque, Edward Bulwer-Lytton, Maffey & Brennall, W. S. Maugham, A. A. Milne, David Christie Murray, Paget Literary Agency, Paramount Pictures, William Dundas Scott-Moncrieff, Lucienne Southgate, Tillotson & Son, Amy Catherine (Robbins) Wells, H. G. Wells, Marjorie (Craig) Wells, W. B. Yeats, and others, dating from 1878 to 1971.
This is a synthetic collection, created from materials acquired through gift and purchase from various sources.
A. P. Watt and Son; Adams, Maude, 1872-1953; Auden, W. H. (Wystan Hugh), 1907-1973; Barham, T. Foster; Besant, Walter, Sir, 1836-1901; Buchan, John, 1875-1940; Chandler, Ernest V; Corelli, Marie, 1855-1924; Doyle, Arthur Conan, 1859-1930; Doyle, Jean Leckie, Lady; Fabulet, Louis, 1862-1933; Garvice, Charles, d. 1920; Gillette, William, 1853-1937; Haggard, H. Rider (Henry Rider), 1856-1925; Jenkins, Edward, 1838-1910; Jones, Meyrick; Kipling, Caroline (Balestier); Kipling, Rudyard, 1865-1936; Little, James Stanley; Lucoque, H. L; Lytton, Edward Bulwer Lytton, Baron, 1803-1873; Maugham, W. Somerset (William Somerset), 1874-1965; Milne, A. A. (Alan Alexander), 1882-1956; Murray, David Christie, 1847-1907; Paget, Harold, b. 1876; Roberts, Michael, 1902-1948; Scott-Moncrieff, William Dundas; Southgate, Lucienne; Vyver, Bertha; Wells, Catherine, 1872-1927; Wells, H. G. (Herbert George), 1866-1946; Wells, Marjorie Craig; Yeats, W. B. (William Butler), 1865-1939; Benn, Ernest, limited, London; Cassell & Company; Doubleday, Page & Company; Field, Roscoe & Company; Heinemann (Firm); J. W. Arrowsmith; Maffey & Brennall; Paget Literary Agency; Paramount Pictures Corporation (1914-1927); Sampson Low, Marston & Company; Tillotson & Son; Correspondence
- Manuscripts and Typescripts, 517455
  - Copyright novels which belong to me. Holograph (?), 1882 Jan.; 517456; ms.; 5 p (Manuscript box)
    With related holograph notes, 2 p. and ms. copy of a list of his works, 3 p.; From the files of A. P. Watt & son
  - 44 memoranda relating to Rudyard Kipling, 1891 - 1939; 517457; ms.; 3 folders (Manuscript box (Kipling))
  - 14 typed memoranda and 9 miscellaneous pieces relating to Marie Corelli, 1915 - 1945; 517458; typescripts; 2 folders (Manuscript box (Corelli))
  - Letters of Charles Dickens to Wilkie Collins. Manuscript list in an unidentified hand. Pages 1-5 written on stationery of A. P. Watt, literary agent. List in an unidentified hand of letters "I recommend should not be sold.", 517459; ms.; 7 p (Manuscript box (Collins, Wilkie))
    Accompanied by 2 ms. receipts, signed by Georgina Hogarth, Feb. 13 and 25, 1890. 1 p.each
  - 100 typed memoranda, notes of conversations, etc., relating to Herbert George Wells, 1926 - 1932; 517460; typescripts; 3 folders (Manuscript box (Wells))
  - 2 typed memoranda, 1 miscellaneous piece relating to William Somerset Maugham, 1949 - 1954; 517461; typescripts; 3 items (Manuscript box (Maugham))
- Financial and Legal Documents, 517462
  - Financial Documents, 517463
    - Royalty statements (10) made out to Mrs. Maxwell [Mary Elizabeth Braddon], 1913 July 31 - 1914 Oct. 14; 517464; financial docs.; 1 folder (Manuscript box (Braddon))
    - [Summary of royalty payments made during April 1898] Typescript, 1898 Apr. 1 - 1898 Apr. 30; 517465; financial docs.; 21 p (Manuscript box)
  - Legal Documents, 517466
    - Agreements (5) between Wilkie Collins or A. P. Watt as agent and George Bentley, Richard Bentley, Chatto & Windus and the Illustrated London news for the publication of his works, 1861 Mar. 11 - 1889 Nov; 517467; legal docs.; 1 folder (Manuscript box (Collins, W.))
      From the files of A. P. Watt & son
    - Agreement between Wilkie Collins and Kelly & Co. for the serial publication of an unnamed novel. In Collins' hand. Draft of proposed memorandum, 1883?; 517468; legal docs.; 2 p (Manuscript box (Collins, W.))
    - Agreement between Wilkie Collins and Kelly & Co. for the serial publication of an unnamed novel. Manuscript copy with Collins' ms. revisions, 517469; legal docs.; 3 p (Manuscript box (Collins, W.))
      Signed for Kelly & Co.; From the files of A. P. Watt & son
    - Agreement between Wilkie Collins and William Frederic Tillotson and William Brimelow for the publication of an unnamed novel [The evil genius]. In Wilkie Collins' hand. Draft of proposed agreement, 1884; 517470; legal docs.; 2 p (Manuscript box (Collins, W.))
    - Agreement between Wilkie Collins and William Frederic Tillotson and William Brimelow for the publication of an unnamed novel [The evil genius]. Manuscript copy of proposed agreement with Collins' ms. revisions, 517471; legal docs.; 3 p (Manuscript box (Collins, W.))
    - Agreement between Wilkie Collins and William Frederic Tillotson and William Brimelow for the publication of an unnamed novel [The evil genius], 1884 Dec. 8; 517472; legal docs.; 3 p (Manuscript box (Collins, W.))
      Signed by Tillotson. With copyright documents for The evil genius from Stationer's hall, Sept. 26, 1885, and the British museum, Sept. 30, 1885; and 2 related receipts from A. P. Watt. From the files of A. P. Watt & son
    - Stationers' company, London. Two memoranda of copyright registration made out to Wilkie Collins for his The victims of circumstantial evidence and The legacy of Cain, 1886 Dec. 16; 1887 Oct. 29; 517473; legal docs.; 1 p. each (Manuscript box (Collins, Wilkie))
- Correspondence, 517474
  - Outgoing Correspondence, 517475
    - Letter books. Letters (copies) to various authors and publishers, etc. Vols. Numbered on spines through XXV. Lacking vols. I, V-VI, XII, XIV, XX-XXIV. Vol. [16] contains letters to or relating to H. Rider Haggard. Each volume indexed separately at front, 1879 Oct. - 1891 June; 517476; corr. out; 16 v (Cased)
      Partial description and list of correspondents laid in vol. [1]. Includes letters addressed to Walter Besant, Hall Caine, Wilkie Collins, A. C. Doyle, Haggard, Bret Harte, Rudyard Kipling and Andrew Lang
    - Auden, W. H. TL (carbon) to. Relates to Oxford book of light verse, 1937 Nov. 23; 517477; corr. out; 2 p (Manuscript box (Auden))
      Came with Watt archive
    - Chappell & Co, Ltd. 2 TL (copies) to. Relate to W. B. Yeats' The Countess Cathleen, 1912 Aug. 13; 1912 Aug. 20; 517478; corr. out; 1 p. each (Manuscript box (Yeats))
    - Corelli, Marie. ALS (draft), 5 AL (drafts), 4 TL (drafts) to, 1906 July 10] - 1911 Feb. 10; 517479; corr. out; 10 letters in 2 folders (Manuscript box (Corelli))
    - Corelli, Marie. 3 TL (carbons) to, 1915 Nov. 16 - 1915 Dec. 10; 517480; corr. out; 3 p. each (Manuscript box (Corelli))
    - Correspondence between A. P. Watt & Son and others. Relates to Marie Corelli's charge that George Gray's The people's king infringed the copyright of her Temporal power, 1913 Jan. 22 - 1913 Feb. 20; 517481; corr. out; 11 letters in 1 folder (Manuscript box (Corelli))
    - Doubleday & Co. 18 TLS, 1 telegram. Relates to Robert Graves, 1948 Mar. 2 - 1971 Nov. 10; 517482; corr. out; 19 letters in 4 folders (Manuscript box (Graves, R.))
      With carbons of 13 letters, 1 telegram, and 1 memorandum from Doubleday to A. P. Watt and son
    - Field, Roscoe & Co. 11 TL (carbons), 6 TN (carbons) and 8 statements of account to. Relate to Marie Corelli, 1916 Mar. 22 - 1945 Feb. 20; 517483; corr. out; 25 letters in 2 folders (Manuscript box (Corelli))
    - Garvice, Charles. TL (copy) to. Relates to agreement between Garvice and Effie Adelaide Maria Albanesi, 1912 Apr. 1; 517484; corr. out; 1 p (Manuscript box (Albanesi))
      With: [Garvice, Charles] TL (carbon) to Effie Adelaide Maria Albanesi. May 19, 1910
    - Maffey & Brentnall. 16 TL (carbons), 6 TN (carbons) to. Relate to Marie Corelli, 1925 Jan. 12 - 1945 Jan. 9; 517485; corr. out; 22 letters in 2 folders (Manuscript box (Corelli))
    - Paget, Harold. 16 TL (carbons) to. Relate to Horace Annesley Vachell, 1913 Nov. 21 - 1915 Jan. 15; 517486; corr. out; 16 letters in 1 folder (Manuscript box (Vachell))
      With two related memoranda
    - Pinker, J. B., & son. 4 TLS to. Relate to Joseph Conrad and Sir Arthur Conan Doyle, 1923 Jan. 29 - 1928 May 15; 517487; corr. out; 1 p. each (Manuscript box (Conrad))
      John D. Gordan bequest
    - Roberts, Michael. TL to. Relates to W. B. Yeats' inclusion in The Faber book of modern verse, 1936, 1935 May 20; 517488; corr. out; 1 p (Manuscript box)
      Signed H. Watt. With envelope; With: Yeats, W. B. TLS to Michael Roberts. Nov. 12, 1935. 1 p.
    - Sampson Low, Marston & Co. Letter to. Relates to Katherine Saunders Cooper, 1880 Aug. 4; 517489; corr. out; 3 p (Manuscript box (Cooper, K. S.))
    - Vyver, Bertha. 4 TL (carbons), 1 TN (carbon) to. Correspondent was secretary to Marie Corelli, 1938 Oct. 17 - 1938 Dec. 21; 517490; corr. out; 5 letters in 1 folder (Manuscript box (Corelli))
    - Ward and Downey. ALS to, 1886 Mar. 15; 517491; corr. out; 1 p (Manuscript box (Harte))
      Encloses Stationers' Hall copyright permit for Britain of Bret Harte's Snow bound at Eagles, March 15, 1886
    - Wells, Herbert George. 49 TL (carbons) to, 1917 Jan. 26 - 1931 Sept. 7; 517492; corr. out; 49 letters in 2 folders (Manuscript box (Wells))
  - Incoming Correspondence, 517493
    - Abbott, John Henry Macartney. ALS to A. P. Watt and son., 1904 Jan. 2; 517494; in. corr.; 2 p (Manuscript box)
    - Adams, Maude. 3 ALS, 9 telegrams to A. P. Watt and son. Relate to the film productions of Rudyard Kipling's stories, 1929 Feb. 14 - 1931 July 11; 517495; in. corr.; 12 letters in 5 folders (Manuscript box (Kipling))
      With 13 TL (carbon) replies and related material including five TLS from Field Roscoe & Co. to Watt enclosing 3 draft agreements
    - Albanesi, Effie Adelaide Maria. ALS to [A. P. Watt and son], 1935 May 23; 517496; in. corr.; 1 leaf (Manuscript box)
    - Arrowsmith, J. W., firm, publishers, Bristol, England. 11 LS to A. P. Watt and son. Relate to Sir Walter Besant and David Christie Murray, 1887 Feb. 11 - 1887 July 22; 517497; in. corr.; 11 letters in 2 folders (Manuscript box (Besant, W.))
    - Bagot, Richard. 2 ALS to A. P. Watt and son, 1903 Feb. 7; 1908 Dec. 7; 517498; in. corr.; 2 p.; 1 leaf (Manuscript box)
    - Baillie-Saunders, Margaret (Crowther). ALS to A. P. Watt and son, n.y.] May 23; 517499; in. corr.; 1 leaf (Manuscript box)
    - Bairnsfather, Bruce. LS, TLS to A. P. Watt and son, 1919 Jan. 13; [n.y.] Mar. 18; 517500; in. corr.; 1 p.; 3 p (Manuscript box)
    - Balchin, Nigel. ANS to A. P. Watt and son, 1944 Feb. 13; 517501; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
    - Baldwin, Stanley Baldwin, 1st earl. AL to A. P. Watt and son, 1943 June 10; 517502; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
      Signed Baldwin of Bewdley. With carbons of two letters from Watt, June 8 and 15, 1943. Relate to Lord Halifax
    - Balfour, Arthur James Balfour, 1st earl of. 2 TLS to A. P. Watt and son, 1922 May 31; 1929 Feb. 28; 517503; in. corr.; 1 p. each (Manuscript box)
    - Bambridge, Elsie (Kipling). ALS to A. P. Watt and son. Relate to Laurence Hanson's inquiries about her father's (Rudyard Kipling's) books, etc., 1940] Dec. 2; 517504; in. corr.; 2 leaves (Manuscript box (Kipling))
      With TL (carbon) reply and memorandum; TLS from Mrs. Bambridge's secretary, Mary e. Walford, Feb. 13, 1945
    - Bannerman, Sir Alexander, bart. ALS to A. P. Watt and son, 1920 June 29; 517505; in. corr.; 2 leaves (Manuscript box)
    - Barham, T. Foster. 7 ALS, 2 TLS, 4 miscellaneous pieces to A. P. Watt and son, 1890 June 5 - 1906 Sept. 25; 517506; in. corr.; 13 letters in 6 folders (Manuscript box (Besant, W.))
      With TL (carbon) reply, Jan. 6, 1911 and five statements of account from the Executors of Sir Walter Besant to Barham and son
    - Baring, Maurice. TLS to A. P. Watt and son. Mentions Hilaire Belloc, 1935 May 24; 517507; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
    - Becke, Louis. LS to A. P. Watt and son. Mentions Walter Jeffery and T. F. Unwin, 1896 May 25; 517508; in. corr.; 5 p (Manuscript box)
      Encloses "List of payments", "Suggested amended agreement between Louis Becke and Walter Jeffery and Messrs. A. P. Watt and son", etc.; with Becke's holograph note on sale of copyrights, 1 p.
    - Beith, John Hay. 4 TLS to A. P. Watt and son, 1933 June 7 - 1935 May 17; 517509; in. corr.; 4 letters (Manuscript box)
      With two TL (carbon) replies
    - Bell, A[--?] H[--?]. 2 ALS to A. P. Watt and son. Relate to Marie Corelli, 1913 Jan. 25; 1913 Jan. 31; 517510; in. corr.; 2 p.; 3 p (Manuscript box (Corelli))
    - Bell, Adrian. ALS to A. P. Watt and son, n.y.] Sept. 24; 517511; in. corr.; 2 p (Manuscript box)
    - Belloc, Hilaire. ALS, ANS to A. P. Watt and son, 1903 July 18; 1903 Aug. 6; 517512; in. corr.; 1 p.; 2 leaves (Manuscript box)
    - Benét, Stephen Vincent. TNS to A. P. Watt and son, 517513; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
    - Benn (Ernest) Ltd. 11 TNS, 6 TNS to A. P. Watt and son. Relate to Essex edition of H. G. Wells, 1926 June 8 - 1932 May 12; 517514; in. corr.; 17 letters in 3 folders (Manuscript box (Wells))
      With carbons of 18 letters from Watt to Benn
    - Benn (Ernest) Ltd. 3 TLS to A. P. Watt and son. Relate to Herbert Cescinsky, 1932 Aug. 23 - 1932 Sept. 7; 517515; in. corr.; 2 p.; 1 p.; 1 p (Manuscript box (Cescinsky))
      With TL (carbon) reply
    - Benson, Edward Frederic. 2 ALS to A. P. Watt and son, 1935 May 18; 1935 May 28; 517516; in. corr.; 1 leaf; 3 p (Manuscript box)
    - Besant, Mary (Garrett), lady. 3 ALS to A. P. Watt and son. Relate to her husband, Sir Walter Besant, 1901] June 15 - [1901] July 8; 517517; in. corr.; 1 leaf; 1 leaf; 1 p (Manuscript box (Besant, W.))
    - Besant, Sir Walter. 1 ALS, 9 ANS, 1 TLS, 7 miscellaneous pieces to A. P. Watt and son. Several letters written as secretary to the Palestine exploration fund, 1884 Feb. 23 - 1899 Jan. 25; 517518; in. corr.; 18 letters in 4 folders (Manuscript box)
      ANS of Feb. 10, 1885 is at bottom of p. 2 of letter from Chatto & Windus to Watt, Feb. 6, 1885; With two letters from Watt, Feb. 26, 1884 and Aug. 19, 1898
    - Besant, Sir Walter. ALS to A. P. Watt and son. Relates to Wilkie Collins, 1890 Feb. 11; 517519; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
      Encloses receipt, ms., signed and dated Feb. 11, 1890. 1 p.
    - Binyon, Laurence. ALS to A. P. Watt and son, 1941 Aug. 13; 517520; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
    - Bird, Kenneth. ALS to A. P. Watt and son, 1935 Nov. 25; 517521; in. corr.; 1 leaf (Manuscript box)
    - Blackett, Spencer C. 5 ALS, 2 LS, 1 note to A. P. Watt and son. Relate to Sir H. R. Haggard, 1887 Sept. 5 - 1890 July 28; 517522; in. corr.; 8 letters in 2 folders (Manuscript box (Haggard))
      With seven printers' certificates and Catalogue of books published by Spencer Blackett & Hallam. London, Sept. 1889
    - Blackwood, Algernon. TLS to A. P. Watt and son, 1915 Oct. 28; 517523; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
    - Blackwood, Algernon. TLS to A. P. Watt and son, 1918 Feb. 17; 517524; in. corr.; 2 p (Manuscript box)
    - Blackwood, Algernon. TLS to A. P. Watt and son, 1949 Dec. 13; 517525; in. corr.; 1 leaf (Manuscript box)
    - Blackwood, Algernon. TLS to A. P. Watt and son, 1950 Mar. 13; 517526; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
    - Bland, Edith Nesbit. 3 ALS to A. P. Watt and son, 517527; in. corr.; 1 leaf; 1 leaf; 3 p (Manuscript box)
      With enclosures of quotations from Shakespeare and others, 7 p.
    - Bodington, Nancy. Postcard to A. P. Watt and son, 1945[?] May 31; 517528; in. corr.; 1 card (Manuscript box)
      Signed Shelley Smith [pseud.]
    - Bolitho, Hector. ANS to A. P. Watt and son. Relates to Philip Lindsay, 517529; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
    - Boyle, Kay. ALS to A. P. Watt and son, 1936 Oct. 19; 517530; in. corr.; 2 p (Manuscript box)
      With carbon of letter from Watt, Oct. 14, 1936
    - Brame, May. ALS to A. P. Watt and son. Relates to copyright of novels by her mother, Charlotte Mary Brame, 1920 Nov. 30; 517531; in. corr.; 3 p (Manuscript box (Brame))
      From the files of A. P. Watt and son
    - Brindley, Martin. 4 ALS to A. P. Watt and son, 1886] July 17 - [1886] July 23; 517532; in. corr.; 1 p.; 2 p.; 1 p.; 1 p (Manuscript box (Watt, A. P.))
      With ALS from Henry Jeula, July 21, 1886
    - Bromfield, Louis. ANS, TLS to A. P. Watt and son, 1935 May]; 1938 Mar. 24; 517533; in. corr.; 1 p. each (Manuscript box)
    - Brophy, John. TLS to A. P. Watt and son, 1934 Feb. 20; 517534; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
    - Buchan, John. 5 TLS, 2 TNS to A. P. Watt and son, 1916 June 19 - 1934 Oct. 12; 517535; in. corr.; 7 letters in 1 folder (Manuscript box)
    - Burgin, George Brown. ALS, TLS to A. P. Watt and son, 1921 Dec. 25; 1935 May 23; 517536; in. corr.; 1 p. each (Manuscript box)
    - Burgin, George Brown. ALS to A. P. Watt and son. Relates to Geoffrey Rhodes, 1937 Sept. 2; 517537; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box. Enclosed in: Rhodes, Geoffrey. TLS to A. P. Watt and son. Sept. 4, 1937)
    - Butler, Samuel. TL (copy) to A. P. Watt and son, 1894 May 25; 517538; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
    - Butler, Samuel. AL (incomplete?) to [A. P. Watt and son], 517539; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
      Encloses his: The life and letters of Dr. Samuel Butler. [London, 1894?] 22 cm. Prospectus. With the author's ms corrections
    - C[--?], A[--?] L[--?]. ALS to A. P. Watt and son, n.y. Mar. 9; 517540; in. corr.; 1 leaf (Manuscript box (Watt, A. P.))
    - Caine, Sir Hall. ALS to A. P. Watt and son, 1887 July (?; 517541; in. corr.; 1 leaf (Manuscript box)
    - Caine, Sir Hall. ALS to A. P. Watt and son, 1887 July 12; 517542; in. corr.; 2 p (Manuscript box)
    - Caine, Sir Hall. ALS to A. P. Watt and son, 1891 Feb. 22; 517543; in. corr.; 2 p (Manuscript box)
    - Caine, Sir Hall. ALS to A. P. Watt and son, 1891 Feb. 23; 517544; in. corr.; 2 p (Manuscript box)
    - Caine, Sir Hall. ALS to A. P. Watt and son. Relates to Wilkie Collins, 1889 Aug. 28; 517545; in. corr.; 2 p (Manuscript box)
    - Campbell, Sir Gilbert Edward, bart. ALS, ANS to A. P. Watt and son, 1891 Feb. 25; [n.d; 517546; in. corr.; 1 p.; 3 p (Manuscript box)
    - Campion, Sarah. 2 TLS, 1 postcard to A. P. Watt and son, 1937 Feb. 20 - 1937 Mar. 24; 517547; in. corr.; 1 leaf; 1 p.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
    - Cardew, [--?]. AL, in the third person, to A. P. Watt and son, 1891 Feb. 7; 517548; in. corr.; 1 leaf (Manuscript box)
    - Carlile, William Warrand. ANS to A. P. Watt and son, 1905 Jan. 5; 517549; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
      Encloses letter to Watt of same date, 3 p.
    - Carstairs, John Paddy. TLS to A. P. Watt and son, 517550; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
    - Carte, Richard D'Oyly. TLS to A. P. Watt and son, 1891 Feb. 23; 517551; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
      With related note in unidentified hand, Feb. 18, 1891. 1 p.; and two TLS from Charles Hawkins, Carte's secretary, Feb. 20 and 24, 1891. 1 p. each
    - Carter, Philip Youngman. ALS to A. P. Watt and son, n.y.] May 23; 517552; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
    - Cassell & Co., Ltd., London. 12 LS to A. P. Watt and son. Relate to Sir Henry Rider Haggard, 1887 May 24 - 1891 Feb. 5; 517553; in. corr.; 12 letters in 2 folders (Manuscript box (Haggard))
      Includes 3 letters written and signed by Sir Thomas Wemyss Reid. Letter of Aug. 2, 1887 encloses royalty statement, dated June 30, 1887
    - Cassell & Co., Ltd., London. 5 TL to A. P. Watt and son. Relate to H. G. Wells, 1928 Nov. 1 - 1931 Mar. 5; 517554; in. corr.; 5 letters in 1 folder (Manuscript box (Wells))
      Signed Newman Flower and Guinivere Davies. With carbons of 4 letters from Watt to Cassell
    - Cassels, Gilbert Robert. ALS to A. P. Watt and son, 1935 May 17; 517555; in. corr.; 2 leaves (Manuscript box)
    - Cescinsky, Herbert. TLS to A. P. Watt and son, 1932 Sept. 9; 517556; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
      With four TL (carbon) replies and one memorandum
    - Chandler, Ernest V. 10 ALS to A. P. Watt and son. Relate to Jeffery Farnol, 1927 Aug. 24 - 1930 Jan. 6; 517557; in. corr.; 10 letters in 3 folders (Manuscript box (Farnol))
      With 6 TL (carbon) and 7 TL (copy) replies, 5 memoranda and 3 misc pieces. Accompanied by: Blanckensee (J.S.) & Co., London. 3 TLS to A. P. Watt and son. Jan. 19-May 19, 1930. With 4 TL (carbon) replies and 2 memoranda
    - Charteris, Leslie. AN, in the third person, to A. P. Watt and son, 1932 Jan. 22; 517558; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
      With carbon of letter from Watt, Jan. 20, 1932
    - Chesterton, Gilbert Keith. LS, TLS to A. P. Watt and son, 1904 Dec.; [1922] Feb. 23; 517559; in. corr.; 1 p.; 2 p (Manuscript box)
    - Chetwynd, Julia Bosville. ALS to A. P. Watt and son, n.y. Mar. 6; 517560; in. corr.; 2 leaves (Manuscript box)
    - Chetwynd, Julia Bosville. ALS to A. P. Watt and son, n.y. Mar. 16; 517561; in. corr.; 3 p (Manuscript box)
    - Chetwynd, Julia Bosville. ALS to A. P. Watt and son, n.y.] Mar. 19; 517562; in. corr.; 1 leaf (Manuscript box)
    - Churchill, Sir Winston Leonard Spencer. ALS to A. P. Watt and son, 1898?] Oct. 27; 517563; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
    - Clark, Sir Kenneth McKenzie. Postcard to A. P. Watt and son, 1946 Jan. 2; 517564; in. corr.; 1 card (Manuscript box)
    - Clifford, Lucy (Lane) ["Mrs. W. K. Clifford"]. 3 ALS, 2 postcards to A. P. Watt and son, 1891] Feb. 16 - [1891] Mar. 3; 517565; in. corr.; 5 letters in 1 folder (Manuscript box)
    - Colles, Richard W. ALS to A. P. Watt and son. Dated from received stamp, 1891 Feb. 3; 517566; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
    - Colles, William Morris. 2 ALS to A. P. Watt and son. Relate to Thomas Wilkinson Speight, 1891 Feb. 6; 1891 Feb. 9; 517567; in. corr.; 2 p.; 1 p (Manuscript box (Speight, T. W.))
    - Collier, Peter Fenelon. TLS to A. P. Watt and son, 1894 Mar. 13; 517568; in. corr.; 3 p (Manuscript box (Haggard))